# Hana Baesmat

Draper, UT

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Hana-Baesmat/e2d68d6274ae463c

A highly motivated technical principal with a demonstrated leadership history, and a passion to establish programs, and continuously improve and contribute to the success of projects and organizations. Adept at conducting research, modelling, and converting simulation models to experiments in lab environments. Specializes in electrical systems design, roadmap planning, and risk mitigation.

# Work Experience

### Sr. Manager, Electrical Engineering Program Management

AMAZON, RELIABILITY MAINTENANCE ENGINEERING (RME) January 2021 to Present

- # Providing electrical engineering support to Amazon sites across North America
- # Providing continuous operational support to the Amazon sites for emergent events
- # Partnering with the global design team to improve Amazon's design practices and criteria
- # Establishing an electrical engineering program across North America addressing electrical safety, asset management, design and specifications, operations and maintenance, and critical risk management
- o Updating the North American Electrical Safety procedure
- o Correcting design deficiencies based on lessons learned and bench-testing of systems
- o Establishing a spare parts management program
- o Establishing an electrical Preventative Maintenance program
- o Establishing a hands-on training program for Amazon's Qualified Electrical Workers (QEW)
- o Developing the North American Electrical Systems Playbook
- # Setting team strategy and goals
- # Headcount management, and growing the electrical team to provide satisfactory coverage of the North American sites

#### **Principal Electrical Engineer**

RIO TINTO - South Jordan, UT May 2019 to January 2021

- # Managing electrical engineering projects:
- o High current rectifier and harmonic filter/capacitor bank upgrades for an electro-winning application
- o 13.8 kV switchgear replacement at Tailings
- o 44kV distribution line re-conductoring and circuit breaker upgrades
- o Site-wide electromechanical to microprocessor-based relay (Schweitzer relays) upgrades
- o Site-wide deployment of SEL-RTAC distribution automation controller
- # Developing the electrical systems roadmap aligned with the business production goals
- o Developing the 5-year roadmap of the electrical systems team to strengthen the power delivery infrastructure, improve the quality of engineering, increase system efficiency and to prepare for the fourth industrial revolution, and grid modernization
- # Developing equipment standards and health criteria

- o Developing standards for VFDs, low voltage Motor Control Centers (MCC), medium voltage switchgears, relays and metering
- o Developing equipment health criteria for power system components
- o Deploying inspections for power systems critical components in the iAuditor and APM platforms
- o Developing the site-wide electrical testing program
- # Providing technical discipline support to major capital projects
- # Providing direction and mentorship to the Kennecott electrical engineers
- # Electrical system design and modeling
- o System modeling and studies in ETAP, SKM, and DIgSILENT PowerFactory
- # Conducting technical risk assessments
- o Criticality assessment of system components
- o Determining equipment testing frequencies based on risk assessments
- # Managing the Electrical Systems Graduate Engineering program and SCADA team
- # Attending Factory Acceptance Tests (FAT) for switchgears, MCCs, transformers, VFDs, etc.
- o Developing equipment specific checklists for FATs

# **Senior Electrical Engineer**

RIO TINTO - South Jordan, UT December 2015 to May 2019

- # Assessing feasibility and soundness of engineering solutions, equipment, and processes
- # Optimizing existing assets and applying complex problem solving techniques
- # Conducting RCAs on electrical systems failures
- o Performing RCAs on the electrical systems failures and implementing the findings to prevent any future reoccurrences
- # Developing auditing tools for equipment data collection
- o Developing an online smart data collection tool to collect data on system components to be used in power system studies
- # Implementing the substation inspection program
- o Deploying an online tool for inspection of critical substations
- o Trending critical parameters of system components
- # Developing equipment specific maintenance procedures, equipment specification, and standard working instructions
- # Conducting load flow, short circuit analysis, protection and coordination, motor transient, and arc flash hazard analysis, and EMT studies
- # Managing the Electrical Systems Graduate Engineering program
- # Programming in RSLogix5000

# **Electrical Engineer**

RIO TINTO KENNECOT - South Jordan, UT October 2012 to November 2015

- # Providing expertise, technical support, reviews, input and technical direction for sustaining capital and expansion projects
- # Reliability of the power distribution system
- o Designating component redundancies based on criticality assessments
- o Using historic data to predict component failures
- o Reviewing transformer oil DGA results
- # Troubleshooting and resolution of ongoing electrical system issues
- # Participates in energy reduction, conservation, and greenhouse gas reduction efforts

- o Peak shaving
- o Site wide power factor improvements
- o Specifying adjustable speed drives where appropriate
- o Reducing power system losses by altering operating procedures, and appropriate design of systems and components
- # Conducting and analyzing power quality studies
- o Conducting PQ studies using the portable ELSPEC PQ meters and analyzing recorded data
- o Providing technical recommendations based on finding

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

UNIVERSITY OF UTAH - Salt Lake City, UT May 2012 to September 2012

# Conducting research on Injectable Wireless Electrode Arrays For Neural Prosthetics

### Manager, Research Department

KURDISTAN ELECTRICAL POWER DISTRIBUTION COMPANY - SANANDAJ, IR February 2009 to October 2011

- # Selecting the best and most efficient research projects proposed by contractors
- # Conducting research projects related to Electrical Power Distribution Systems
- # Managing research projects through completion

# **Electrical Design Engineer**

KURDISTAN ELECTRICAL POWER DISTRIBUTION COMPANY - SANANDAJ, IR September 2007 to February 2009

- # Technical and Economic planning of Electrical Power Distribution Systems
- o Design of low voltage power distribution systems including lines, transformers, protection devices, capacitors, etc.
- # Launching the Power Distribution Equipment Monitoring Software

#### Education

#### **Doctorate in Electrical Engineering**

UNIVERSITY OF UTAH - Salt Lake City, UT December 2019

#### **Master's certificate in Project Management**

GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY - Washington, DC November 2015

#### **Master in Electrical Engineering**

UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN February 2010

### **Bachelor in Electrical Engineering**

UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN

February 2007

## Skills

- Self-motivated
- Flexible
- Team player
- Problem solving
- Converting simulation models to experiments in a lab environment
- Optimization
- · Machine learning
- Knowledge of MSHA/OSHA requirements
- Schweitzer relays
- RSLogix5000
- FAA certified drone pilot
- Root Cause Analysis
- ACES Lean Six Sigma
- Expert in MATLAB/SIMULINK/SIMSCAPE
- SKM
- AIMMS
- DIgSILENT PowerFactory
- PSCAD
- SynchroWAVe Event
- MS Office
- LaTeX
- AutoCAD
- Knowledge of IEEE
- FERC
- NERC
- NEC
- NFPA70E
- NFPA 70B
- NETA MTS standards

# Certifications and Licenses

# **Certified Project Manager**